<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sleepmode</title>
    <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sleepmode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:58:11 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Melee Is Sick, and I Don&#39;t Want to Play It</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/melee-is-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:58:11 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/melee-is-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten older, more mature and more experienced with the fighting game genre, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to become pretty good at honestly assessing my feelings about particular games. This honesty really reached a strong point of development when I finally realised that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like BlazBlue Central Fiction all that much (you can read about that in my article &amp;ldquo;Learning to Love, to Learn and to Let Go&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s come to carry forward into another game which I&amp;rsquo;ve had a fraught relationship with &amp;ndash; Super Smash Bros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIKKE: First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/nikke-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 21:50:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/nikke-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do the whole mobile game thing. They&amp;rsquo;re usually massive time sinks and even larger money sinks, almost always without any actual engaging gameplay to back them up. This was set to change when I found out about a recently released mobile game called Goddess of Victory: NIKKE, a &amp;ndash; fucking god damn it not again
When seeing people talk about NIKKE, it would be centered on one of two ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimising a Vroid Model for VRChat</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/vroid-vrchat-optimisation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 17:13:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/vroid-vrchat-optimisation-guide/</guid>
      <description>A pretty popular and accessible way of creating custom avatars for VRChat is by using Vroid Studio, a program mostly used to create character models for vtubers. Unfortunately, VRChat has pretty strict limitations on how avatar models can actually be constructed and displayed in a session without setting people&amp;rsquo;s computers on fire1, and Vroid models by default will flagrantly ignore all those limitations in the pursuit of making your brand new anime femboy self-actualisation vehicle as cute as programmatically possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evo 2022 Announcement Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/evo-announcement-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 19:25:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/evo-announcement-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve missed every discourse cycle for the past few months and god damn it I will not miss this one when there is #content to be created.
Anyway, here are my scattered thoughts on some of the bigger announcements that were made at the 2022 edition of Evo, everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite fighting game trade show masquerading as a tournament.1
Capcom Capcom revealed two new characters for the upcoming Street Fighter 6 &amp;ndash; Juri Han and Kimberly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spectator&#39;s Guide to Bloody Roar Extreme</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/spectator-guide-brex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 18:09:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/spectator-guide-brex/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again: Combo Breaker is almost upon us. Of the many FGC majors sprinkled throughout the US, the Chicago, IL event is most notable for its emphasis on spotlighting novel, commuinty-driven brackets &amp;ndash; most notorious are its Mystery Game and Auction tournaments, including the cultural touchstone that was the Sarvets All-Stars tournament from 2018. And while these kinds of events are almost certainly appearing at Combo Breaker 2022, the main stage will also be seeing a new challenger among the likes of Guilty Gear Strive and The King of Fighters XV &amp;ndash; a Nintendo Gamecube game called Bloody Roar Extreme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOF XV Balance Change Proposals</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 03:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing The King of Fighters XV a lot lately. I think the game is very good, and overall the balance is pretty spot-on, but there are a few things that I think warrant some changes &amp;ndash; nothing drastic, just a few quality of life changes here and there. I&amp;rsquo;m putting them all here so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to see them all over your timeline. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to justify every proposal I&amp;rsquo;m making here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Love, to Learn and to Let Go</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 20:57:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</guid>
      <description>Prior to Guilty Gear Strive and Dragon Ball FighterZ, Arc System Works&amp;rsquo; three most prolific and popular fighting games were Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R, Guilty Gear Xrd Rev2 and BlazBlue Centralfiction. These are all games I&amp;rsquo;ve spent varying &amp;ndash; but generally large &amp;ndash; amounts of time with, and my opinions of them have varied accordingly. My rocky relationship with all three of these games is well-documented, here and elsewhere, but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a pretty clear idea of how I feel about all these games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:14:11 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Socials twt/SleepmodeAU
I (unfortunately) use Twitter a lot, and will probably continue to use it until it implodes due to one man&amp;rsquo;s unfathomable arrogance and ineptitude. Follow me there to keep up with my day-to-day thoughts on things and maybe even make fun of me for them.
fedi/Sleepmode@gayrobot.club
I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the Fediverse for a while, mostly just bumming about on my friend&amp;rsquo;s instance. This will mostly be relevant to you if you&amp;rsquo;re on FGC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:33:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>In my last piece, I may have said a few things about my feelings on Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R and BlazBlue Central Fiction. Those feelings may have been largely negative feelings where I admitted my frustrations and losses came from a lack of knowledge, but then I rationalised my lack of desire to play these games as simply not wanting to fill those gaps in my knowledge.
I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like I was scrubquoting hard in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleepmode&#39;s 2021 Gaming Recap</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 15:52:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</guid>
      <description>So 2021 happened. I was originally going to introduce this piece with a brief overview of the political situation under COVID-19 as a way to contrast how awful the year was with some personal levity, but the idea of jumping from &amp;ldquo;the far right is growing out of an anti-vaccine movement while governments continue to glibly allow their citizens to die from a preventable disease and ordinary people try pick up the slack where their leaders and fascist/fascist-adjacent neighbours have failed&amp;rdquo; to talking about the video games I played this past year felt like a bit too strong of a tonal whiplash.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
