<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 16:10:54 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Playing OutRun 2SP in $CURRENT_YEAR</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/outrun-2-in-current-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 16:10:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/outrun-2-in-current-year/</guid>
      <description>In 1986, a man named Yu Suzuki, along with a small handful of developers at SEGA AM2, would release an arcade racing game called OutRun. Suzuki had previously made some fairly successful motorcycle racing games for SEGA by way of Hang-On and Enduro Racer, and with OutRun, he sought to create a racing game predicated primarily on allowing players to enjoy the experience of driving and, in his words, &amp;ldquo;feel superior&amp;rdquo;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combo Expression</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/combo-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 23:56:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/combo-expression/</guid>
      <description>You guys don&amp;rsquo;t fucking know how to talk about anything. I mean, I know that Twitter as a format is basically anathema to actual discussion but you could at least try.
The Twitter account FightstickArt, ostensibly an account centered on showing off people&amp;rsquo;s cool fight sticks and artwork and stuff, took part in the time-honoured tradition of engagement farming by posing a question to FGC twitter: what&amp;rsquo;s most important to you in a fighting game?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleepmode Year In Review: 2022 Edition</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2022-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 20:37:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2022-recap/</guid>
      <description>So, uh. I guess 2022 wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly 2021 Hard Mode, but we can&amp;rsquo;t exactly say there were many&amp;hellip; systemic improvements to the stuff that was fucked about last year, either. I&amp;rsquo;m at least doing okay on a personal level, which means I&amp;rsquo;m in a better position to be working with others to fight for those systemic improvements at least!
Anyway, this is gonna go on mostly the same beat as the last one of these, though it&amp;rsquo;s not gonna be focused exclusively on games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melee Is Sick, and I Don&#39;t Want to Play It</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/melee-is-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:58:11 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/melee-is-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten older, more mature and more experienced with the fighting game genre, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to become pretty good at honestly assessing my feelings about particular games. This honesty really reached a strong point of development when I finally realised that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like BlazBlue Central Fiction all that much (you can read about that in my article &amp;ldquo;Learning to Love, to Learn and to Let Go&amp;rdquo;), and it&amp;rsquo;s come to carry forward into another game which I&amp;rsquo;ve had a fraught relationship with &amp;ndash; Super Smash Bros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimising a Vroid Model for VRChat</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/vroid-vrchat-optimisation-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 17:13:32 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/vroid-vrchat-optimisation-guide/</guid>
      <description>A pretty popular and accessible way of creating custom avatars for VRChat is by using Vroid Studio, a program mostly used to create character models for vtubers. Unfortunately, VRChat has pretty strict limitations on how avatar models can actually be constructed and displayed in a session without setting people&amp;rsquo;s computers on fire1, and Vroid models by default will flagrantly ignore all those limitations in the pursuit of making your brand new anime femboy self-actualisation vehicle as cute as programmatically possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evo 2022 Announcement Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/evo-announcement-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 19:25:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/evo-announcement-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve missed every discourse cycle for the past few months and god damn it I will not miss this one when there is #content to be created.
Anyway, here are my scattered thoughts on some of the bigger announcements that were made at the 2022 edition of Evo, everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite fighting game trade show masquerading as a tournament.1
Capcom Capcom revealed two new characters for the upcoming Street Fighter 6 &amp;ndash; Juri Han and Kimberly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spectator&#39;s Guide to Bloody Roar Extreme</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/spectator-guide-brex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 18:09:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/spectator-guide-brex/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again: Combo Breaker is almost upon us. Of the many FGC majors sprinkled throughout the US, the Chicago, IL event is most notable for its emphasis on spotlighting novel, commuinty-driven brackets &amp;ndash; most notorious are its Mystery Game and Auction tournaments, including the cultural touchstone that was the Sarvets All-Stars tournament from 2018. And while these kinds of events are almost certainly appearing at Combo Breaker 2022, the main stage will also be seeing a new challenger among the likes of Guilty Gear Strive and The King of Fighters XV &amp;ndash; a Nintendo Gamecube game called Bloody Roar Extreme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOF XV Balance Change Proposals</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 03:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing The King of Fighters XV a lot lately. I think the game is very good, and overall the balance is pretty spot-on, but there are a few things that I think warrant some changes &amp;ndash; nothing drastic, just a few quality of life changes here and there. I&amp;rsquo;m putting them all here so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to see them all over your timeline. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to justify every proposal I&amp;rsquo;m making here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Love, to Learn and to Let Go</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 20:57:22 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</guid>
      <description>Prior to Guilty Gear Strive and Dragon Ball FighterZ, Arc System Works&amp;rsquo; three most prolific and popular fighting games were Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R, Guilty Gear Xrd Rev2 and BlazBlue Centralfiction. These are all games I&amp;rsquo;ve spent varying &amp;ndash; but generally large &amp;ndash; amounts of time with, and my opinions of them have varied accordingly. My rocky relationship with all three of these games is well-documented, here and elsewhere, but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a pretty clear idea of how I feel about all these games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:33:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>In my last piece, I may have said a few things about my feelings on Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R and BlazBlue Central Fiction. Those feelings may have been largely negative feelings where I admitted my frustrations and losses came from a lack of knowledge, but then I rationalised my lack of desire to play these games as simply not wanting to fill those gaps in my knowledge.
I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like I was scrubquoting hard in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleepmode&#39;s 2021 Gaming Recap</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 15:52:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</guid>
      <description>So 2021 happened. I was originally going to introduce this piece with a brief overview of the political situation under COVID-19 as a way to contrast how awful the year was with some personal levity, but the idea of jumping from &amp;ldquo;the far right is growing out of an anti-vaccine movement while governments continue to glibly allow their citizens to die from a preventable disease and ordinary people try pick up the slack where their leaders and fascist/fascist-adjacent neighbours have failed&amp;rdquo; to talking about the video games I played this past year felt like a bit too strong of a tonal whiplash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create.</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:14:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/creativity/</guid>
      <description>I used to be very insecure about my creative ability.
This insecurity has long since passed, now that I&amp;rsquo;m older and generally more confident, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that I do reflect on from time to time. After all, when you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by so many people who can do incredible things &amp;ndash; visual artists, graphic designers, musicians, voice over artists and just about everything else you can think of &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to feel like you need to &amp;ldquo;measure up&amp;rdquo; to them in some way, and equally hard not to feel discouraged or even depressed when you can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;create&amp;rdquo; works of art the way the people around you are seemingly able to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Players Are Not Stupid Pt.2</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-players-are-not-stupid-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 22:45:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-players-are-not-stupid-2/</guid>
      <description>I think, fundamentally, engaging with any video game (but especially a fighting game) is akin to a conversation between developer and player.
As a developer, your goal should be to confidently communicate your game&amp;rsquo;s mechanics to your player, and trust that the player will be able to keep up. There&amp;rsquo;s a delicate balance here, though &amp;ndash; say too little, and your player won&amp;rsquo;t feel comfortable contributing to the conversation on their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exodus</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 16:03:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/exodus/</guid>
      <description>Welcome.
This is my new blog, hosted on Github Pages and running on Hugo (after much fighting with inscrutable software dev nerd shit). It&amp;rsquo;s here because I got sick of Wordpress being clunky and locking useful quality of life features behind a paywall. Hopefully this way you won&amp;rsquo;t need uBlock Origin so much.
For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, the old blog is not being deleted, just deprecated &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping all of my old writings there for archival purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 21:29:12 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Orin (aka Sleepmode)
I&amp;rsquo;m an Australian video game enthusiast with a particular love of fighting games and arcade-style tests of skill. This place is usually where you can find me writing about that, and sometimes other things. Older writings can be found on my Wordpress Blog, which is no longer in use because I hate QOL features being locked behind a paywall.
Links to my Twitter, Twitch and Youtube channels can all be found in the sidebar, as well as on my links page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
