<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Sleepmode</title>
		<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Sleepmode</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 03:01:58 +1000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>KOF XV Balance Change Proposals</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 03:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/kofxv-change-wishlist/</guid>
			<description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing The King of Fighters XV a lot lately. I think the game is very good, and overall the balance is pretty spot-on, but there are a few things that I think warrant some changes &amp;ndash; nothing drastic, just a few quality of life changes here and there. I&amp;rsquo;m putting them all here so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to see them all over your timeline. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to justify every proposal I&amp;rsquo;m making here.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been playing <em>The King of Fighters XV</em> a lot lately. I think the game is very good, and overall the balance is pretty spot-on, but there are a few things that I think warrant some changes &ndash; nothing drastic, just a few quality of life changes here and there. I&rsquo;m putting them all here so you don&rsquo;t have to see them all over your timeline. I&rsquo;ll try to justify every proposal I&rsquo;m making here. This is by no means complete, and there are a lot of characters that I can&rsquo;t speak on, so feel free to make your own thoughts and opinions known to me. I appreciate the discussion.</p>
<p><strong>EDIT (11/03/2022):</strong> I forgot that Athena could do the funny Freeza ball super in the air, so the change to make Psycho Sword &gt; Shining Crystal Bit consistent midscreen was unnecessary. Just do the funny Freeza ball.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="system">System</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Reduce movement input lockout on run to 6F<br>
<em>Please god just let me move around more. I get that SNK wanted to make movement a bit more committal but this is just ridiculous. Movement being the way it is right now actually contributes a lot to zoning being as strong as it is, too.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Change 4214 inputs back to 421<br>
<em>Why was this change made? We didn&rsquo;t change DP motions to 6236. This just screws up anyone who instinctively ends on 1 for these motions and there&rsquo;s no real reason for it to be this way.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ángel">Ángel</h2>
<ul>
<li>Increase frame advantage on Finish: Grapple Kick (Unchain Finish 236C)<br>
<em>Given that this is the ender for one of Ángel&rsquo;s most consistent light confirms, the fact that it both gives her minimal frame advantage and sends the opponent full screen kind of hurts. It shouldn&rsquo;t be enough to guarantee a safejump or anything, but it should be enough to let Ángel actually gain meaningful ground after landing it.</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ash-crimson">Ash Crimson</h2>
<ul>
<li>Reduce lower hurtbox on 4D/6D so it can go over lows<br>
<em>While Ash is built around using pressure resets to force mistakes, his lack of character-specific mixup tools means the mistakes he wants to force are basically just pseudo-frame traps and whiff punishes. A great way to supplement this is by making his Floreal series go over low attacks, which it doesn&rsquo;t currently do. This would give Ash an excellent means of beating low-commitment checks on his pressure.</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="iori-yagami">Iori Yagami</h2>
<ul>
<li>Increase range on 6A<br>
<em>Some characters get to have far crazier buttons they can cancel for a combo. Iori should be allowed to have his arms back.</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="joe-higashi">Joe Higashi</h2>
<ul>
<li>Reduce stun damage on Bakuretsuken (623P)<br>
<em>Just to make his guaranteed stun combos less accessible.</em></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="kula-diamond">Kula Diamond</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Decrease startup time on f.C<br>
<em>Why does this button have like a year&rsquo;s worth of startup frames? More characters have long-range buttons that lead to good reward while being much faster than this button currently is, and since &ldquo;cancelling far buttons&rdquo; was Kula&rsquo;s thing first, she deserves to still be good at it.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Increase j.A hitbox horizontally behind Kula<br>
<em>SNK gave Kula a cross-up button and then chickened out halfway through by making it almost impossible to actually use for its intended purpose. I hardly think that Kula would be broken if she had a functional cross-up.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Remove knockdown property from second hit of EX Falling Snowman (22AC)<br>
<em>The funny friend setplay projectile doesn&rsquo;t even work midscreen, the very least that should be done is letting it actually be useful in the corner.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ralf-jones">Ralf Jones</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Reduce upper hitbox on f.D<br>
<em>I&rsquo;m completely okay with Ralf being a footsies monster in this game, but he&rsquo;s already got far C to control the skies, and far D also being able to do that turns it into a button that just does everything for him. A footsies monster should have to pick and choose their pokes, which is what this change should do.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Increase recovery on non-EX versions of Dynamite Ralf Punch (214P)<br>
<em>Ralf can whiff this pretty safely right now, which is quite strong considering that its upper-body invulnerability makes it a pretty nice anti-air. You&rsquo;d want to increase the recovery enough to allow consistent whiff punishes from slight distances, but not so much that he can&rsquo;t use it as a way to delete fireballs from a larger distance.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="ramón">Ramón</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Allow 3D to combo after A normals<br>
<em>I&rsquo;m just gonna chance the idea that he&rsquo;d be a much more stable character if he had better combos from lights than&hellip; [checks notes] 2B into Rush Combo. Fuckin, yikes, dude.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reduce startup on 2C and 5CD<br>
<em>Ramón has two pretty decent pokes in these buttons, which are held back by being dirt slow. Speeding up 2C just makes it a more viable footsie tool (which he kind of sorely needs), and speeding up 5CD not only does that, but would also allow him to combo into it after 3D Quick Max, which would help his ability to cash out combos with Climax, since 5CD is his only real way to land a level 1 cross chop super.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="shermie">Shermie</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Allow super cancels from Shermie Cute (236K after Shermie Spiral/Clutch)<br>
<em>Currently, Shermie only wants to use Shermie Cute if it will win the round, because it absolutely kills her oki otherwise. A damage/oki trade-off is totally okay, but if we&rsquo;re going to make her make that decision, then at least let her do some DAMAGE like Clark can.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reduce knockback on EX Shermie Cute (236K after EX Shermie Spiral/Clutch)<br>
<em>Shermie has this really cool extension after EX Spiral and Clutch where she can do a microdash into Shermie Whip. Unfortunately, this is prohibitively difficult, which isn&rsquo;t ideal considering that her ability to get a follow-up after EX Cute is extremely limited if she doesn&rsquo;t want to immediately cash out a super. Ideally you&rsquo;d reduce the knockback so that you don&rsquo;t have to microdash to get the Whip.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="terry-bogard">Terry Bogard</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Increase recovery time on C Burn Knuckle (214C) so that it isn&rsquo;t plus on block from long distance<br>
<em>So like, we can all agree that this is the main thing that makes Terry absolutely cracked, right? The guy is basically using it as a movement option, and it&rsquo;s a powerful one, considering that he gets in for free when he does it. Using the funny advancing special as a burst movement option should be Andy&rsquo;s thing, anyway.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reduce pushback on block for EX Crack Shoot (214BD) so all characters can throw punish<br>
<em>EX Crack Shoot is a 16F overhead. This would be absolutely fucked if it did more damage or started a combo, but fortunately, it does neither of those things, so I think Terry should keep it because it&rsquo;s funny. What&rsquo;s less funny is that even if the opponent guesses right, he&rsquo;s still safe because he&rsquo;s -2 with pushback on block. Allowing everyone to punish this with a throw on block seems like a good counterbalance to an unseeable &ndash; but pretty low reward &ndash; overhead.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="vanessa">Vanessa</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Increase recovery of Dash Puncher ([4]6P)<br>
<em>Not sure if I want it punishable or just to make it so her turn is Definitively Over if it gets blocked, but it definitely needs to not be as safe as it is. I mean, it&rsquo;s basically Sol Badguy&rsquo;s Grand Viper, she should have to take on some of the risk that Sol takes on with his funny low profile advancing launcher.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reduce launch height of Puncher Upper (6A after Puncher Vision) so that C Dash Puncher does not connect<br>
<em>The use of C Dash Puncher in Vanessa&rsquo;s corner juggles is the primary factor in the absolutely insane damage of her 0.5 bar combos. This change acts to bring her damage in line without significantly changing her combo theory. She&rsquo;s still getting great damage off that 2B, don&rsquo;t worry.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="whip">Whip</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Allow early hit of 3A to cancel to special moves<br>
<em>Currently, Whip&rsquo;s combos are very very inconsistent, especially since she lost the ability to use parts of her Strength Shot series as combo pieces from XIV. Letting her do something like cl.C 3A into a special move seems like it would be fine.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Restore the first hit of Strength Shot &ldquo;Code: Strength&rdquo; (63214B)<br>
<em>This move currently does actually nothing. Sure it&rsquo;s plus on block and starts a combo on hit, but like. Who cares? It takes so long to impact that no one is ever going to just sit there and take it. Letting her have a real pressure reset option would give Whip a way to actually enforce what little regular KOF she gets to play.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reduce knockback on EX Strength Shot Type A &ldquo;Code: Superior&rdquo; (63214AC)<br>
<em>The idea here is to allow Whip to use 2D as a follow-up to this move outside of the corner. Her combos in general kind of suck, so giving her this much seems warranted.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>I hope all of this seems sensible. Again, let me know what you think. This is an interesting discussion to have!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Learning to Love, to Learn and to Let Go</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 20:57:22 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/love-learn-let-go/</guid>
			<description>Prior to Guilty Gear Strive and Dragon Ball FighterZ, Arc System Works&#39; three most prolific and popular fighting games were Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R, Guilty Gear Xrd Rev2 and BlazBlue Centralfiction. These are all games I&amp;rsquo;ve spent varying &amp;ndash; but generally large &amp;ndash; amounts of time with, and my opinions of them have varied accordingly. My rocky relationship with all three of these games is well-documented, here and elsewhere, but I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a pretty clear idea of how I feel about all these games.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Prior to <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em> and <em>Dragon Ball FighterZ</em>, Arc System Works' three most prolific and popular fighting games were <em>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R</em>, <em>Guilty Gear Xrd Rev2</em> and <em>BlazBlue Centralfiction</em>. These are all games I&rsquo;ve spent varying &ndash; but generally large &ndash; amounts of time with, and my opinions of them have varied accordingly. My rocky relationship with all three of these games is well-documented, here and elsewhere, but I feel like I&rsquo;ve come to a pretty clear idea of how I feel about all these games. That&rsquo;s what we&rsquo;re talking about this time.</p>
<h2 id="learning-to-love-guilty-gear-xrd-and-new-perspectives">Learning to Love: Guilty Gear Xrd and New Perspectives</h2>
<p><em>Guilty Gear Xrd</em> is a game which made a great first impression on me, and then gradually lost its appeal the more I began to understand what it was doing. I &ndash; along with lots of other people &ndash; did not like the effect that the game&rsquo;s Yellow Roman Cancel had on its pacing, decision-making and general flow. It&rsquo;s a very, <em>very</em> powerful mechanic, and whether or not you can vibe with it decides whether or not you can vibe with the game as a whole. While I wasn&rsquo;t expecting my opinion on <em>Xrd</em>&rsquo;s YRC to change any time soon, my experience with <em>ACPR</em> (which I&rsquo;ll be outlining soon) left me wondering if I&rsquo;d come away from more time spent with <em>Xrd</em> &ndash; a game I hadn&rsquo;t played in years &ndash; feeling more positive about it.</p>
<p>The answer to that question is&hellip; kind of?</p>
<p>Recently, I played a long set with my day-one <em>Rev2</em> Venom against my friend <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Toneblerones">Toneblerone</a> and his region-dominating Jack-O'. I didn&rsquo;t go in expecting to win, especially when coming up against a character as heavy on the knowledge checks as Jack-O', but man, that didn&rsquo;t feel good. And she&rsquo;s mid-tier?</p>
<p>Anyway, my overwhelming impression coming from <em>Rev2</em> is that it&rsquo;s definitely a game that I like more than I dislike, because for all of its elements that I don&rsquo;t fully appreciate, it&rsquo;s still largely based on a fighting game that I genuinely do like. I&rsquo;d like to say that I have problems with the way <em>Xrd</em>&rsquo;s new characters were designed, but my lack of experience with the game&rsquo;s high level meta, combined with my slightly more extensive background in <em>ACPR</em><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> is like. Do I get any right to complain? They are at least mechanically interesting, especially in the case of Jack-O' and Ramlethal.</p>
<p>I did, however, have my dislike of YRC heavily solidified. I&rsquo;m not opposed to &ldquo;pause button&rdquo; mechanics in fighting games on principle, and I&rsquo;m definitely fine with <em>Xrd</em>&rsquo;s trademark slowdown on the game&rsquo;s other Roman Cancels, but YRC does so much, and so well, for so little cost, comparatively speaking. There are certainly interesting things you can do with it, and I don&rsquo;t want to discount that, but the fact that there are so few restrictions on it, on top of the way that RC slowdown eats your opponent&rsquo;s inputs and even grants you some invincibility when you perform it just makes it so, like, unbelievably strong, but more importantly, it&rsquo;s strong in a very homogeneous way. Not everyone uses YRC in exactly the same ways, but everyone can take advantage of it in similar enough ways that it just makes the mechanic feel less interesting than any of the war crimes <em>ACPR</em>&rsquo;s cast can commit, even if said war crimes are (in)arguably more egregious than doing move &gt; YRC &gt; air throw.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;d play very much <em>Rev2</em> if it got rollback, but I definitely feel more sympathetic towards the people that would. People love this game, and despite my mechanical gripes, I completely understand why they do. All signs point to this game not getting a rollback update (at least not in any official sense), but it really does deserve one.</p>
<h2 id="learning-to-learn-accent-core-r-and-attitude-adjustment">Learning to Learn: Accent Core +R and Attitude Adjustment</h2>
<p>I love this game. No, really! I know what I&rsquo;ve said about the game in the, uh, <a href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap">very recent past</a>, but&hellip; okay, let me tell you what happened.</p>
<p><em>Guilty Gear</em> &ndash; the entire thing, not just <em>Accent Core</em> &ndash; is a very selfish game. This is how Lord Knight described the game, but while he meant it in the sense that &ldquo;every player hates every character that isn&rsquo;t their own&rdquo;, I mean it in the sense that <em>Guilty Gear</em> is a game where your success as a player is contingent almost entirely on locking your opponent out of their ability to play the game &ndash; it&rsquo;s a real &ldquo;mom said it&rsquo;s my turn on the Xbox&rdquo; kind of experience. Which makes sense &ndash; every character is capable of some truly <em>abominable</em> stuff<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> &ndash; and understanding this is key to getting maximum enjoyment from the game. It took me a good while to understand that.</p>
<p>See, I&rsquo;ve &ldquo;quit&rdquo; <em>ACPR</em> a few times now. I&rsquo;ve run the gamut of excuses, blaming my opponents, myself, even both at the same time! But despite all my complaining about &ldquo;the Australian Regional Meta&rdquo; and whatever, whenever I stopped playing, I kept feeling like I still wasn&rsquo;t giving the game a fair chance. I said I&rsquo;d rather pick the bullshit that I like, but do I really, actually dislike <em>ACPR</em>&rsquo;s brand of bullshit? Or am I just giving up because I don&rsquo;t get easy-mode answers to the problems that are most commonly presented to me?</p>
<p>I determined that it was the latter. So I came back one last time, trying to keep my mind as open as possible, not just to what my opponents might want to do, but also to novel ways to approach the game as a whole. In doing so, I discovered the true beauty of <em>ACPR</em> &ndash; it&rsquo;s a game where there&rsquo;s always a strategy or technique I&rsquo;ve never thought of, an answer I&rsquo;d never considered.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> And while my ideas don&rsquo;t always pan out &ndash; Justice is still a pain in the ass to fight &ndash; my capacity to come up with new ideas is making the experience feel much more rewarding.</p>
<p>Also, for what it&rsquo;s worth, my newfound attitude towards this game has once again allowed me to both appreciate the game&rsquo;s sense of humour even more, AND truly recognise when my opponents do Genuinely Cool Shit. It&rsquo;s good to be back.</p>
<h2 id="learning-to-let-go-blazblue-and-the-end-of-a-shared-history">Learning to Let Go: BlazBlue and The End of a Shared History</h2>
<p>One of my gateways into competitive fighting games was picking up a copy of <em>BlazBlue Continuum Shift</em> for the Xbox 360. Being a fresh &lsquo;09-er, hot off the heels of <em>Street Fighter IV</em> and <em>Tekken 6</em>, I had no idea what I was getting myself into,<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> but it set me on a path that I&rsquo;d basically be stuck on &ndash; to this day, my main group of friends in the FGC, both locally and abroad, is a bunch of Anime Players. In a sense, I kind of owe where I am right now to <em>BlazBlue</em>. Which might explain why it took me so long to accept that I&rsquo;m just not cut out for this shit.</p>
<p>I want to begin this by saying that, despite its very troubled history, <em>BlazBlue</em>&rsquo;s most recent iteration, <em>Centralfiction</em>, is inarguably a good fighting game. It&rsquo;s pretty well-balanced, there&rsquo;s a generally high power level among most of the cast, and there&rsquo;s a lot of fun to be had with the wildly divergent and creative tools available to players. But, as a consequence of that, <em>BlazBlue</em> is a game that has <strong>a lot</strong> going on, and it demands that you learn not just its systems, but pretty deeply learn the functions of each character in order to properly engage with it. After the game got its rollback netcode update, playing it a lot more made me realise that I am unable, and perhaps unwilling, to meet that demand.</p>
<p>Now, this might sound like I&rsquo;m complaining about losing to everyone because of matchup knowledge, and that&rsquo;s kind of true &ndash; you will get got by a ton of tools in this game because you don&rsquo;t know what they&rsquo;re doing, or what they look like, or how it behaves in relation to each other tool the character is using. A frankly disconcerting number of those tools are attached to characters whose primary gimmick is making the screen immensely difficult to look at, adding &ldquo;don&rsquo;t look at the thing that&rsquo;s actually hitting you&rdquo; to the list of knowledge checks you need to pass before you can start properly interfacing with the character.</p>
<p>But for all of the dense, layered puzzle-box characters to contend with, of all the Sega rhythm game-inspired gimmicks to play through, what truly took me out of <em>BlazBlue</em> was, interestingly enough, its wakeup mechanics.</p>
<p><em>BlazBlue</em>, similarly to some 3D fighting games, gives you a bevy of ukemi options to utilise after a knockdown. On top of quick getup and a <em>massive</em> delay getup window, you can also tech roll forward and backward. In theory, this should make okizeme an interactive and thoughtful game state that requires good reads and intimate knowledge of your character&rsquo;s options to properly capitalise.<br>
This is not the case. Perhaps this is less a consequence of the systems themselves and more of the way character tools have been designed and redesigned as the series has gone on, but playing the game was an exercise in learning that just about every competent character is capable of making this wide variety of wakeup options almost completely irrelevant, thanks to basically every knockdown leading to a meaty that will check delayed getup and both tech rolls while still allowing them to get another meaty into guaranteed pressure if you happen to quick getup.<br>
This dynamic is only compounded by the fact that most of those competent characters have pretty easy access to a hard knockdown, which removes your ability to quick getup entirely, forcing you to interface with the game&rsquo;s other wakeup options. The way the controls for these wakeup options work, though, means you can&rsquo;t just hold down-back and A+B to wake up in place with Barrier &ndash; because holding down-back after a hard knockdown will give you a fairly punishable back roll. And instances where forward roll is a good idea are few and far between, so most of the time, the best way to get up from a hard knockdown is to tech, and then not hold down any directions until you see the tech animation.<br>
They put a character whose primary reversal is a <strong>flash kick</strong> into an environment like this. Don&rsquo;t pick Kagura Mutsuki.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not that I disagree with strong okizeme or anything like that,<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> it&rsquo;s just that dealing with the okizeme in <em>BlazBlue</em>, at least for me, feels really bad. Like, it just sucks knowing that you have this suite of wakeup options, and that like half of them lose to your opponent timing a meaty 2A. It feels like the game is lying to me.<br>
Maybe I&rsquo;m just a fighting game oyaji after all, at the ripe old age of 27, but I think there&rsquo;s something to be said for a game being content to tell me that the way to deal with an oppressive tool or setup is, &ldquo;you don&rsquo;t&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I did honestly try to properly learn <em>BlazBlue</em>. I hit the lab, I read the wiki, I talked about the game and problem matchups. I couldn&rsquo;t make it stick. I wasn&rsquo;t really comfortable thinking about how a game that defined my early years as a fighting game player was one that I didn&rsquo;t actually enjoy all that much, but maybe it&rsquo;s okay that I don&rsquo;t. It&rsquo;s not like I learned nothing from the experience, and it&rsquo;s not like the friends I made because of it aren&rsquo;t going away, either. Something that fighting games are pretty good at is teaching you about yourself, and it may just be that &ldquo;Sleepmode really is just a fucking old man&rdquo; is a lesson I was finally ready to learn.</p>
<p>All of these games are cool, though. Play <em>ACPR</em> with me. Or play <em>BBCF</em> with someone who can handle that game. I would tell you to play <em>Rev2</em>, but I don&rsquo;t know if my conscience can handle telling you to play a game with netcode from the stone age, even if it&rsquo;s not really anyone&rsquo;s fault that we&rsquo;re in this situation. Then again, if the <em>Samurai Shodown</em> players can survive through <em>that</em> netcode, then maybe there&rsquo;s hope after all.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>As in, the game with Testament&rsquo;s Badlands loops, Zappa&rsquo;s busted-ass Sword ghost, Dizzy&rsquo;s unthrowable j.2S, and Justice&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>A.B.A. is like, a bottom three character, but if you fail to prevent her from activating Moroha (or even worse, Goku Moroha) then you probably just die right there&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I feel like I definitely picked the right character for that, too &ndash; I play Venom, and remembering that I can set balls in the air as waypoints to move around the screen was a gamechanger&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
<p>The era of <em>BlazBlue</em> spanning <em>Calamity Trigger</em> to <em>Continuum Shift Extend</em> was notoriously a not very good one, but everyone pretended that those games were worth taking seriously anyway&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Dude, I play <em>Guilty Gear</em> and <em>SoulCalibur</em>, two games with some of the most soul-crushing okizeme known to man.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>My New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:33:52 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-years-resolution/</guid>
			<description>In my last piece, I may have said a few things about my feelings on Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R and BlazBlue Central Fiction. Those feelings may have been largely negative feelings where I admitted my frustrations and losses came from a lack of knowledge, but then I rationalised my lack of desire to play these games as simply not wanting to fill those gaps in my knowledge.
I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like I was scrubquoting hard in doing so.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/">my last piece</a>, I may have said a few things about my feelings on <em>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R</em> and <em>BlazBlue Central Fiction</em>. Those feelings may have been largely negative feelings where I admitted my frustrations and losses came from a lack of knowledge, but then I rationalised my lack of desire to play these games as simply not wanting to fill those gaps in my knowledge.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t help but feel like I was scrubquoting <em>hard</em> in doing so.</p>
<p>Like, boo hoo, you don&rsquo;t like that you don&rsquo;t know how to deal with Order Sol pressing Jump Heavy Slash? You&rsquo;re sad that it requires more effort for you to deal with A.B.A. mashing Danzai than it does for the A.B.A. to mash Danzai in the first place? Frustrated that you lost to Lambda because you literally just don&rsquo;t know how she works? Grow up.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>People are prone to saying shit when they get heated &ndash; especially me, being a highly opinionated man and all. Like for god&rsquo;s sake, I have a <em>blog</em>. The only way I could get more self-aggrandizing about my own opinions is if I hosted my own podcast to platform them. And my opinions can be&hellip; muddled, let&rsquo;s say, in the face of emotional distress of any kind.</p>
<p>So. A new year&rsquo;s resolution for 2022:<br>
I resolve to not say <strong>anything</strong> when I get salty. Nothing at all. Shut the fuck up.<br>
When I&rsquo;m covered in salt up to my eyeballs, I will shut my ass up, and go do something else.<br>
Lab another fighting game. Boot up some <em>Crimzon Clover</em>. Turn on the PS2 and bust some heads in <em>Time Crisis</em>.<br>
Do literally <strong>anything</strong> except say words that probably won&rsquo;t be reflective of my thoughts a week later.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s to a 2022 of continual attitude adjustment.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I still reserve the right to complain about Justice, though.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Sleepmode&#39;s 2021 Gaming Recap</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 15:52:54 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/2021-games-recap/</guid>
			<description>So 2021 happened. I was originally going to introduce this piece with a brief overview of the political situation under COVID-19 as a way to contrast how awful the year was with some personal levity, but the idea of jumping from &amp;ldquo;the far right is growing out of an anti-vaccine movement while governments continue to glibly allow their citizens to die from a preventable disease and ordinary people try pick up the slack where their leaders and fascist/fascist-adjacent neighbours have failed&amp;rdquo; to talking about the video games I played this past year felt like a bit too strong of a tonal whiplash.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So 2021 happened. I was originally going to introduce this piece with a brief overview of the political situation under COVID-19 as a way to contrast how awful the year was with some personal levity, but the idea of jumping from &ldquo;the far right is growing out of an anti-vaccine movement while governments continue to glibly allow their citizens to die from a preventable disease and ordinary people try pick up the slack where their leaders and fascist/fascist-adjacent neighbours have failed&rdquo; to talking about the video games I played this past year felt like a bit too strong of a tonal whiplash. This preamble has done nothing to avoid that whiplash, but at least I tried.</p>
<p>Anyway, I played some video games in 2021. Let&rsquo;s talk about them.</p>
<h3 id="guilty-gear-strive-i-guess">GUILTY GEAR STRIVE, I GUESS</h3>
<p><a href="https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-players-are-not-stupid-2/">I&rsquo;ve said my piece on this game.</a> I won&rsquo;t repeat myself too much here, but suffice to say &ndash; I do not like this game. It replaced everything I liked about <em>Guilty Gear</em> with subtly (or sometimes overtly) worse versions of those things, and made the things I didn&rsquo;t like about <em>Guilty Gear</em> even worse &ndash; when it wasn&rsquo;t replacing them with something that exchanged my frustration for boredom, anyway. But hey, the people playing it are enjoying themselves, so you don&rsquo;t have to listen to me. I&rsquo;m not really the target audience for this game, and shockingly, probably not any <em>Guilty Gear</em> game.</p>
<h3 id="acpr-got-rollback-and-now-i-hate-it">ACPR GOT ROLLBACK AND NOW I HATE IT</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a saying that gets brought up every now and then in the fighting game community &ndash; &ldquo;picking a fighting game is about picking what bullshit you&rsquo;re willing to deal with&rdquo;. Over time, I&rsquo;ve found that sentiment to be less and less convincing. Learning and improving at a fighting game will inevitably be frustrating sometimes, but I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s a sign of healthy engagement when you simply learn to &ldquo;deal&rdquo; with the things that frustrate you &ndash; there should, I think, be some amount of motivation to learn how to get past these challenging, frustrating elements based on curiosity and intrigue, instead of just an obligation to do so because you&rsquo;re gonna have to figure it out at some point anyway.</p>
<p>When <em>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R</em> got its miraculous rollback netcode update (with continuous QOL improvements up until the end of 2021), I very soon learned that the frustrating part of that game, for me, was the Australian Regional Meta. In places like Japan and the US, playing <em>ACPR</em> will get you a decent amount of character variety and a broad assortment of skill levels and playstyles. In Australia, you get an environment dominated by Justice, Order-Sol and A.B.A. doing Their One Thing over and over until they win, refusing to ever move past layer one. Every loss feels shameful, and every victory feels pyrrhic. Of course, I&rsquo;m well past trying to blame my losses on anyone but myself, and while the knowledge that I could learn how to overcome these frustrations lingers in the back of my mind, a question remains: do I want to? And the answer is always a resounding &ldquo;no&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I dunno, maybe I&rsquo;ve just hit my &ldquo;fighting game oyaji&rdquo; phase a decade early, but these days I just don&rsquo;t have the time or the energy to try and motivate myself to learn what&rsquo;s required of me when what I&rsquo;d have to learn seems far more annoying than compelling. I don&rsquo;t want to pick the bullshit I want to deal with &ndash; I want to pick the bullshit that I like.</p>
<h3 id="flycast-got-rollback-and-now-i-am-living-my-best-life">FLYCAST GOT ROLLBACK AND NOW I AM LIVING MY BEST LIFE</h3>
<p>When I found out that developer &ldquo;flyinghead&rdquo; had somehow implemented GGPO netplay into their Sega Dreamcast emulator <em>Flycast</em>, it was through me waking up to about five different people telling me about it on social media. I couldn&rsquo;t believe it then, and I can&rsquo;t believe it now, even though I&rsquo;ve spent more time playing <em>Project Justice</em>, <em>Virtua Fighter 3tb</em> and <em>SoulCalibur</em> with people from all across Australia and the world than I ever expected to. Hell, I spent even more time than that playing <em>Capcom vs SNK 2</em>, so maybe I really have hit my &ldquo;fighting game oyaji&rdquo; phase. Games from this particular era, on this particular set of hardware &ndash; Dreamcast, NAOMI and Atomiswave &ndash; are probably among my favourite in the genre, and despite how easily I get distracted, I always find myself coming back to them eventually. These games are just magical for me &ndash; they&rsquo;re always fun, and anything that&rsquo;s frustrating is often equally funny.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s likely only a matter of time before I become the <em>Hokuto no Ken</em> player I was always meant to be. In the meantime, see me in <em>SoulCalibur</em> or <em>The King of Fighters XI</em>.</p>
<h3 id="i-tried-slippi-one-last-time-and-melee-finally-made-sense-to-me">I TRIED SLIPPI ONE LAST TIME AND MELEE FINALLY MADE SENSE TO ME</h3>
<p>The first time I tried getting into <em>Super Smash Bros. Melee</em>, back when Slippi first released its rollback netplay functionality for the game, the experience nearly made me quit fighting games. Having the army of netplay Falcos dance all over my flailing body while I could barely get the game to do anything I wanted it to do showed me a unique kind of helplessness that no amount of looping unblockable setplay could ever make me feel.<br>
The second time I simply resolved that the game is cool, but not for me. Far too much effort involved in learning how to properly manipulate my character to make it worthwhile.<br>
The third time, I finally got it. I still don&rsquo;t actively play the game, mostly for the same reason as the second go around, but now it&rsquo;s a game that <em>could</em> be for me &ndash; a younger me with more free time and brain cells to rub together. As the saying goes &ndash; <em>Melee</em> is sick.</p>
<p>&hellip;wait, what do you mean <a href="https://twitter.com/FaultyPine/status/1467605279244271621?s=20">someone&rsquo;s starting to get rollback working in <em>Brawl</em>?</a></p>
<h3 id="i-finally-installed-outrun-2-fxt-and-i-am-vibing-to-magical-sound-shower-right-now">I FINALLY INSTALLED OUTRUN 2 FXT AND I AM VIBING TO MAGICAL SOUND SHOWER RIGHT NOW</h3>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have much more to add to this. Control settings are finicky because it&rsquo;s a port of an Xbox game from 2006, but the <a href="http://dragonking.arcadecontrols.com/static.php?page=AboutFXT">&ldquo;OutRun 2 FXT&rdquo; mod</a> for Sega&rsquo;s masterpiece, <em>OutRun 2</em><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> adds a lot of compatibility options for modern displays and operating systems. I&rsquo;m gonna have to get a racing wheel for this at some point.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s this section. <em>OutRun 2</em> is one of the greatest video games ever made. It&rsquo;s also technically abandonware, so you have no excuse not to <a href="https://archive.org/details/OUTRUN2006C2C">download it</a><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> and play it right now.</p>
<h3 id="i-played-a-bunch-of-shmups-and-have-not-become-competent-at-any-of-them">I PLAYED A BUNCH OF SHMUPS AND HAVE NOT BECOME COMPETENT AT ANY OF THEM</h3>
<p>My good friend <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Pichy_And_Pals">Pichy</a> bought me a copy of <em>Deathsmiles</em> a couple years ago, and this genre has been stuck in my peripheral vision ever since then. I have not completed a playthrough of the game more than once, and in the preceding years I bought myself <em>Crimzon Clover WORLD IGNITION</em> and <em>ZeroRanger</em>. I have not completed either.</p>
<p><em>Crimzon Clover</em> is a game I have very little to say about, but only because I&rsquo;ve played so little of it. It feels great and the game showering you with item pickups and massive score multiplier displays helps create a lot of the Happy Brain Chemical. I may very well get sucked into it more if I boot it up on a whim again, but I&rsquo;m also on a search for the one shmup that just hooks me. I&rsquo;m sure it&rsquo;s out there.</p>
<p><em>ZeroRanger</em>, on the other hand, is a game that I found pretty frustrating in the beginning &ndash; its colour palette made a lot of enemy ships and their bullets weirdly difficult for me to keep track of. And yet, at no point does the game&rsquo;s challenge feel unfair, at least once I got past that first hurdle. I&rsquo;m still somewhere in the second loop, and while I haven&rsquo;t gone back to it in a while, I definitely understand why people recommended it to me. It manages to be very forgiving with its stage unlocks and continue system, while also desigining those systems in a way that makes them feel almost a bit unforgiving. I don&rsquo;t know if this is a game I&rsquo;d actually want to learn seriously, but it&rsquo;s cool.</p>
<h3 id="my-arcade-got-taiko-no-tatsujin-and-i-am-this-close-to-getting-my-own-bachi">MY ARCADE GOT TAIKO NO TATSUJIN AND I AM THIS CLOSE TO GETTING MY OWN BACHI</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m pretty fortunate to have a fairly active community of rhythm game players that like to head to the arcade at a pretty central shopping destination near my house. We all initially coalesced around <em>Dance Rush Stardom</em>, a BEMANI game where the entire gimmick is that you are quite literally using Melbourne Shuffle dance techniques to play it, but the growing presence of dedicated players alongside the general broad appeal that music games have to passers-by has led to a slight expansion of available rhythm games. It started with <em>Dance Dance Revolution A</em> (and later <em>A20</em>), then an old <em>DrumMania</em> cabinet, and soon after we were bombarded with <em>Maimai DX</em>, <em>Pump It Up</em> and a guitar-side <em>Gitadora</em> cabinet. The latest addition to that collection is Bandai Namco&rsquo;s <em>Taiko no Tatsujin</em>, and it might be my new favourite rhythm game?</p>
<p>One of the strengths of rhythm games as a genre is that they&rsquo;re usually pretty easy to learn, but nigh impossible to truly master. The curve doesn&rsquo;t look the same between all games, however &ndash; a game like <em>Beatmania IIDX</em> has a pretty high skill floor and only gets more intense from there, while a game like <em>Guitar Hero</em> is pretty easy to pick up thanks to a simple control scheme and lack of variable timing windows, but caps out the skill ceiling at a strange level where most of the difficulty comes from figuring out how to most efficiently hit the increasingly dense note patterns that crop up as the game&rsquo;s high-level meta continues to progress. <em>Taiko no Tatsujin</em> feels like it&rsquo;s probably got the most balanced learning curve of just about any rhythm game I&rsquo;ve played this side of <em>DDR</em>. With only two ways to hit the drum, the game gets you hooked by establishing a solid base that allows you to feel like you&rsquo;re pretty damn good at the game &ndash; the road to improvement, then, comes from learning how to properly parse the beatmap and knowing the best way to guide your hands around the drum. It wouldn&rsquo;t be the first time that an instrument-based rhythm game has been more demanding than actually playing the real instrument, but that just adds to the lasting appeal.</p>
<h3 id="deltarune-chapter-2-came-out-so-i-played-through-the-whole-thing-again">DELTARUNE CHAPTER 2 CAME OUT SO I PLAYED THROUGH THE WHOLE THING AGAIN</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s been pretty cool seeing Toby Fox grow and evolve as an artist. <em>Undertale</em> is as famous as it is for a reason, and while it stuck with me much as it did everyone else, it&rsquo;s not necessarily for the same reasons. I&rsquo;ve always been more interested by the themes present in these games rather than their explicit lore or narrative, and while it was a bit hamfisted in some respects, it was pretty interesting seeing the things that <em>Undertale</em> had to say about the way people engage with violence in video games. Not like the hamfistedness is a bad thing &ndash; Yoko Taro has basically made a career out of it, and Fox&rsquo;s first non-ROM hack effort tackles the subject with a lot more tact than Taro, in many regards. So when Fox released the second chapter in his new episodic work, <em>Deltarune</em>, I felt it pertinent to go through the first chapter again, if only because the last time I had played it was when it came out in 2018.</p>
<p>These games are charming like nothing else, and the entire <em>Deltarune</em> dev team has done a lot to improve and build on much of the core experience of <em>Undertale</em> while also leveraging new ideas and mechanics to make the game more compelling and fun as a game as well as a narrative and general thought exercise. Thematically, <em>Deltarune</em> seems to be very concerned with the idea of agency &ndash; when the player controls a character in a game world, are they the character, or the player? Are they both? Where does one end and the other begin? Who is the one making the decisions, and whose decisions are the ones that actually matter? This exploration of the relationship between player and player character is one that&rsquo;s pretty novel, at least to me, and I was pretty impressed by the ways in which the two available chapters explore that question in different ways.</p>
<p>The writing is also fantastic in other areas, of course. The game&rsquo;s irreverent, slightly bewildering sense of humour is not only intact from <em>Undertale</em>, but also much improved in quality, in a way that really understands what the Extremely Online people who play these games find funny &ndash; which, of course, includes cartoon splat noises and stock explosion effects that have been bundled with <em>Game Maker</em> since version 6. Special mention has to be given to Queen specifically in chapter 2 &ndash; that character is a fucking riot.</p>
<p>Both chapters are free if you haven&rsquo;t played them already. I highly suggest you do. Now stop talking about Gaster.</p>
<h3 id="bbcf-got-rollback-and-now-i-hate-it">BBCF GOT ROLLBACK AND NOW I HATE IT</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a saying that gets brought up every now and then in the fighting game community &ndash; &ldquo;picking a fighting game is about picking what bullshit you&rsquo;re willing to deal with&rdquo;.</p>
<p>For the longest time, I thought <em>BlazBlue Central Fiction</em> was &ldquo;the bullshit I was willing to deal with&rdquo;. After all, alongside the usual suspects that were <em>Street Fighter IV</em> and <em>Tekken 6</em>, one of the first fighting games I tried to seriously learn as a competitor was <em>BlazBlue Continuum Shift Extend</em>. I&rsquo;ve been with this series for a long time, and after finding a character I grew to love in <em>Chronophantasma Extend</em>&rsquo;s Kagura Mutsuki, I thought I&rsquo;d be with it for a good while longer now that the game has functional online play.</p>
<p>This is not the case. I cannot handle this game &ndash; not any more, anyway. I earnestly tried to learn about and understand each of the game&rsquo;s characters, who are all designed like dense and inscrutable puzzle boxes, but when those characters aren&rsquo;t filling the screen with nonsense and hitting me with moves that are overheads despite not looking meaningfully distinct from anything else they could be doing, they&rsquo;re turning every hit into a 15-second combo whose knockdown creates a safejump that also invalidates most of the game&rsquo;s unwieldy wakeup options.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the energy or the patience for this shit any more. Part of me wonders if <em>BlazBlue Cross Tag Battle</em> will be a more positive experience for me, if only because the game respects my time enough to just fucking kill me if I get hit, but somehow, I doubt it.</p>
<h3 id="kusoge-advent-calendar-2021">KUSOGE ADVENT CALENDAR 2021</h3>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t already know, I&rsquo;m part of the so-called &ldquo;committee&rdquo; of people who decide on games to be featured on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WQhAcigABBw&amp;list=PLmq6bEN5THET4hmFmZDIQwliJDDOdiOSu">Kusoge Advent Calendar</a>, a yearly marathon hosted on my friend AJ&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/tyronesama">Twitch channel</a> where they play approximately one bad/weird/occasionally good fighting game every day from the start of December until Christmas. I invite you to go through the playlist and see what happens, but some standouts from this year were:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Garouden Breakblow: Fist or Twist</em>, which is not so much a &ldquo;fighting game&rdquo; as much as it is a &ldquo;game about fighting&rdquo;. Each of the game&rsquo;s hits feel weighty and impactful, and the way the camera zooms in during the early phases of a match where both players trade blows in a weird kind of damage race only sells the impact of those hits even more. Coupled with the game&rsquo;s unique tug-of-war life bar and bodily damage systems, <em>Garouden Breakblow</em> delivers a keen sense of drama that I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ve seen in any other fighting game, or that many games, full stop. It&rsquo;s an absolute blast to play with friends, too &ndash; if you&rsquo;ve got a PS2 (or a laptop), you should definitely take this to a local.</li>
<li><em>WeaponLord</em>, but only because playing it ended up being more of a historical discussion about the mindset of Western fighting game developers in the 90s, as well as a deep dive into &ldquo;XBAND&rdquo;, a service that allowed SNES and Sega Mega Drive owners to play games with others online, over a <em>dial-up internet connection</em>. Of particular note is that <em>WeaponLord</em> was the only XBAND-compatible game which advertised said compatibility on the box because it was built for XBAND from the ground-up &ndash; this is important because for every other game that was played over XBAND, the creators of the service had to <em>reverse-engineer those games in order to get the damn thing to work</em>. We talked about that instead of playing <em>WeaponLord</em>, because <em>WeaponLord</em> is not a very good game.</li>
<li><em>Vs.</em>, a game whose reputation as &ldquo;the weird localisation of <em>Fighter&rsquo;s Impact</em>&rdquo; absolutely does not do it justice. This game is absolutely wild, with insane guard break mechanics and some questionable moves that take advantage of those mechanics, but it&rsquo;s a standout among 3D fighting games on the PSX solely for the fact that it actually controls well and runs at a good framerate &ndash; something usually only achieved by Namco&rsquo;s offerings of the time.</li>
<li><em>Spectral Vs. Generation</em>, a game which stands as a testament to just how much Taiwanese developer IGS was able to learn about making fighting games in its roughly ten years of doing so.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> While it&rsquo;s not without busted and highly exploitable jank, the game has a baseline good feel with some grime to get into even without jumping into the various infinites it allows, and the characters all feel fairly strong and functional. It&rsquo;s a good time, and it&rsquo;s on Fightcade!</li>
<li><em>The Untouchable</em>, because&hellip; look, just watch the VOD. I promise you won&rsquo;t be disappointed.</li>
</ul>
<p>These things are always a great time, and I&rsquo;m always thankful for everyone else on the committee for being so courteous in the face of me inevitably screwing around their schedule because of the fake-ass timezone I live in. See you in December.</p>
<h3 id="the-king-of-fighters-xv-x-dnf-duel-a-tale-of-two-betas">THE KING OF FIGHTERS XV X DNF DUEL: A TALE OF TWO BETAS</h3>
<p>These two games are what gives me hope for the genre outside of Fightcade. <em>KOFXV</em> had a beta before the one it held in December &ndash; concurrently with <em>DNF Duel</em> &ndash; but I&rsquo;ll just lump the experience of both betas in together.</p>
<p><em>KOFXV</em> is basically what I expected it to be &ndash; a sequel to <em>KOFXIV</em>, which naturally means that it is really good. I had faith in SNK to create a satisfactory game to begin with, because they haven&rsquo;t felt the need to drastically shake up what <em>KOF</em> fundamentally is<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, and building on the systems and design philosophy of <em>KOFXIV</em> moving into the new entry was a great decision. Game felt good, online play was flawless (at least in the second beta, where it counts), and I&rsquo;m excited to spend more time with it when it releases.</p>
<p>Now, <em>DNF Duel</em>. This was originally going to get its own whole write-up, but I&rsquo;ve done enough screaming about it anyway so I&rsquo;ll just commit a section here to it instead.<br>
8ing, developers of all sorts of wacky and fun fighting games from the <em>Naruto: Clash of Ninja</em> series to <em>Ultimate Marvel vs Capcom 3</em>, are nothing short of legends in the FGC &ndash; known for just running with their ideas and throwing consequence to the wind, they could always be relied on to provide a game that was just good old-fashioned Fighting Game Absurdity when other games failed to meet expectations. But when we needed them most, they vanished &ndash; their last proper fighting game effort in a long while being <em>Steel Combat</em>, a 2016 release made exclusively for Oculus VR systems after they were bought by Colopl. But when Neople, developers of old-as-time action MMORPG <em>Dungeon Fighter Online</em>, announced that they were collaborating with Arc System works to create a fighting game based on their online game, one detail was pretty inconspicuously popped in at the end of the trailer.<br>
8ing was back. And boy, are they back.</p>
<p>8ing has always had a few common threads between all of their fighting games &ndash; simple but flexible controls, massive hitboxes and wacky non-standard resource management.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> All of the above is here in full force, and it&rsquo;s hard not to feel like this is a return to form for 8ing. ArcSys&rsquo;s production helps reign in some of 8ing&rsquo;s artistic excesses<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup> while also helping the game to look gorgeous and play exceptionally well online thanks to its rollback netcode. Each character feels powerful in unique and idiotic ways, from Berserker&rsquo;s stationary Gore Cross projectile backing up his &ldquo;my footsies nice&rdquo; normal attacks, to Striker&rsquo;s divekick that reverse beats into seven overheads, to Crusader&rsquo;s righteous hammer comboing into itself like five times in the corner he just made for himself. This game is beautiful and hilarious in a way I thought the industry had left behind, and the game I played is basically the game I want &ndash; Grappler infinites and all. The only change I&rsquo;d make is to tone down the methods each character can use to remove white life, since the prevalence of white life removal in even basic combos meant that people didn&rsquo;t really get to play around with the game&rsquo;s &ldquo;Conversion&rdquo; mechanic, a system which effectively acts like <em>Tatsunoko vs Capcom</em>&rsquo;s &ldquo;Baroque&rdquo; mechanic, except it turns your recoverable life into meter instead of damage. This is a really cool mechanic with a lot of potential, and I think the game would hugely benefit from giving players more opportunities to actually use it.</p>
<p>When almost every new fighting game out there wants me to be smart, thoughtful or just to play in a certain way, 8ing has made <em>DNF Duel</em>, a game which asks only that I fuck around and find out. That&rsquo;s the energy I need going into 2022.</p>
<h3 id="i-finally-started-hackgu-and-this-is-why-you-did-not-see-me-for-two-months">I FINALLY STARTED .HACK//G.U. AND THIS IS WHY YOU DID NOT SEE ME FOR TWO MONTHS</h3>
<p>The <em>.hack</em> games have always been on the sidelines for me, waiting for me to finally dive into them. I&rsquo;ve been familiar with the series for a long time, having watched its two main anime seasons, <em>.hack//SIGN</em> and <em>.hack//Roots</em> back when I was in high school and thoroughly loving both of them. I&rsquo;d attempted to play the original <em>.hack</em> quadrilogy once before, but found the first game, <em>.hack//Infection</em>, to be unreasonably punishing in many respects despite the fact that I absolutely adore the way it commits to the feel of being an MMORPG from the early 2000s. Of course, those games being PS2-exclusive (as of this writing) renders them fairly inaccessible as well, which fortunately cannot be said for its follow-ups, the <em>.hack//G.U.</em> games &ndash; <em>Rebirth</em>, <em>Reminisce</em> and <em>Redemption</em> &ndash; which are all available alongside a brand-new fourth episode, <em>Reconnection</em>, in the HD remaster bundle <em>.hack//G.U. Last Recode</em>. I have thoroughly loved the experience, and while I&rsquo;m not quite done with the series just yet, I finished the first two episodes before the end of the year so I&rsquo;m gonna say that counts.</p>
<p>While the <em>G.U.</em> games forego some of the feel of playing a janky MMORPG in favour of a more player-friendly action-RPG combat system, the general presentation remains, and it uses that presentation as its key asset as a means of diegetically expanding the game&rsquo;s lore &ndash; from the player character&rsquo;s PC desktop, you can log into &ldquo;The World R:2&rdquo;, the game within the game where most of the story takes place, you can read and reply to emails in order to explore and build relationships with other characters, or read the news and community forums to get a sense of what&rsquo;s going on in the world outside of the game. There&rsquo;s a lot to love about the <em>.hack</em> franchise, but this presentation style, for me, is chief among them.</p>
<p>It also helps that the story is quite compelling as well, with a lot of threads involving how online spaces affect the ways we perceive both ourselves and others, the ways in which corporate malice and/or incompetence can make these spaces actively harmful and dangerous, and what it means to truly connect with people you care about. There are also a lot of beating stuff up with giant swords and scythes and gunblades and summoning your digital stand so you can fight viruses that look like giant spiders made out of slime. It&rsquo;s pretty rad.</p>
<p>Speaking of giant swords and what-have-you, the core gameplay is pretty fun as well, with the action-RPG combat system lending itself to a fair amount of fun and expressive ways to engage enemies, especially as you progress and unlock more weapon types to use, as well as figure out how to utilise the game&rsquo;s pretty generous windows for cancelling attacks into skills or the recovery of those attacks into a guard. You can even bounce enemies of the wall for funky juggles, and while you&rsquo;re not gonna be seeing a <em>.hack//G.U.</em> combo MAD any time soon, it still feels pretty sick pulling off a crazy extended wall bounce combo with repeated animation cancels. It&rsquo;s all helped by a really flexible equipment customisation system, with slotted abilities on weapons, armour and accessories able to be added or removed on a whim, and all of those abilities being items that can be found in dungeons. The system allows you to really make how you play the game your own, while also allowing you to freely experiment with different builds at any given time without making you rely on getting specific equipment sets.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t speak for what the experience would have been like back when these games were first releasing on the PS2, but <em>.hack//G.U.</em>&rsquo;s episodic structure<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup> really helps sell the drama and tension of key elements of the game&rsquo;s narrative, as well as helping to set clear points to measure the growth of the main character, Haseo &ndash; a classic &ldquo;jerk with a heart of gold&rdquo; archetype who only pushes people away for fear of losing them. No wonder this guy is voiced by Takahiro Sakurai. The entire main cast is all a lot of fun to spend time with, each with their own quirks, hang-ups and interesting motivations &ndash; especially Atoli, whose initial portrayal as innocent and optimistic to the point of naivety, sets her up to be an excellent foil to the jaded loner that Haseo is introduced as, giving both characters a jumping off point from which they can learn important lessons about themselves and become better people as a result. It also helps that Atoli is very very cute and I love her dearly.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re interested, I would definitely recommend picking the game up. It&rsquo;s on Steam, and is usually pretty cheap when it goes on sale.</p>
<hr>
<p>So that was my 2021 in video games. It wasn&rsquo;t all peachy, to be sure, and I learned some things about my taste in fighting games that I was maybe not prepared to learn, but I still had a good time overall. Here&rsquo;s hoping 2022 is when we start to get out of this mess. In the meantime, stay safe, wear a mask, and be good to each other.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s to a 2022 that is hopefully not just 2021 (Hard Mode).</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Or <em>OutRun 2006: Coast to Coast</em> if you want to split hairs.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Shout outs to <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Zeether77">Zeether</a> for the upload &ndash; you&rsquo;re a real one.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Can you believe the people who made <em>Spectral Vs. Generation</em> also made <a href="https://youtu.be/_tmx1FOOJSo?t=1022"><em>Alien Challenge</em>?</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
<p>They tried that hardest with <em>KOFXII</em>, which I&rsquo;ll go to bat for, but not for very long.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
<p>After all these years, they&rsquo;re still making <em>Battle Garegga</em>, god bless&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Super cinematics only go for like, five seconds instead of twenty-five lmao&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Which might be among the first examples of episodic video game releases?&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Create.</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/creativity/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:14:37 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/creativity/</guid>
			<description>I used to be very insecure about my creative ability.
This insecurity has long since passed, now that I&amp;rsquo;m older and generally more confident, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that I do reflect on from time to time. After all, when you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by so many people who can do incredible things &amp;ndash; visual artists, graphic designers, musicians, voice over artists and just about everything else you can think of &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to feel like you need to &amp;ldquo;measure up&amp;rdquo; to them in some way, and equally hard not to feel discouraged or even depressed when you can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;create&amp;rdquo; works of art the way the people around you are seemingly able to.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to be very insecure about my creative ability.</p>
<p>This insecurity has long since passed, now that I&rsquo;m older and generally more confident, but it&rsquo;s something that I do reflect on from time to time. After all, when you&rsquo;re surrounded by so many people who can do incredible things &ndash; visual artists, graphic designers, musicians, voice over artists and just about everything else you can think of &ndash; it&rsquo;s hard not to feel like you need to &ldquo;measure up&rdquo; to them in some way, and equally hard not to feel discouraged or even depressed when you can&rsquo;t &ldquo;create&rdquo; works of art the way the people around you are seemingly able to.<br>
Of course, the creation of art, and &ldquo;creativity&rdquo; in general, doesn&rsquo;t actually work like this. If societies and the people in them are, as Marx once put it<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, products of their own material cicumstances, then it&rsquo;s pretty safe to say that each individual person&rsquo;s art, whatever shape it may take, is simply the culmination of every work of art they&rsquo;ve ever engaged with. Not exactly a new idea &ndash; &ldquo;there are no truly original works&rdquo; is kind of just a fact of art as a whole. But, y&rsquo;know, there are plenty of artistic pursuits where the artists not only draw on influences from other works, but create art that is entirely contingent on the existence of works made by others. I want to talk about those works, and why they can comfortably be called &ldquo;art&rdquo;.</p>
<p>But first, listen to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MbFyubsqKCE">this song</a>.</p>
<p>The artist known only as &ldquo;pluffaduff&rdquo; has been at this mashup business for a while now, but started gaining notoriety a few years ago when their musical creations were picked up on by high-profile members of the <em>Clone Hero</em> content creation sphere, primarily Acai and JasonParadise. Mashups have been around in music spheres for a <em>long-ass time</em> &ndash; they&rsquo;re a staple part of any self-respecting DJ&rsquo;s repertoire &ndash; but artists like pluffaduff really highlight just how much creativity, energy and passion go into a form of musical composition that can only exist because countless others have composed countless pieces of music before them. There&rsquo;s novelty to it, sure, but it&rsquo;s also an entirely new listening experience that feels more like a part of the artist than of any of the other artists whose works went into the final product&rsquo;s composition.</p>
<p>Now, read <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2021/11/cowboy-bebop-netflix-review-1234678880/">this review of Netflix&rsquo;s <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> adaptation</a>. I promise we won&rsquo;t actually spend that much time talking about <em>Cowboy Bebop</em>.</p>
<p>Obviously, the existence of this adaptation in and of itself is proof of the ability to create something <em>mostly</em> new<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> out of someone else&rsquo;s creation, I think the more pertinent point to focus on is this particular review of the adaptation. David Ehrlich spends time talking about the moral and artistic merits of adapting <em>Cowboy Bebop</em> in this way, as well as in general, and spends much time discussing what the original show has to say, and consequently, what its adaptation completely misses. Again, this is not peculiar &ndash; literary analysis and artistic criticism have existed since forever. But it&rsquo;s the way that these analyses and critiques are used to discuss broader ideas about the concept of <em>Cowboy Bebop</em>, and of filmmaking as a whole, in some respects, that shows just what goes into art criticism. And it&rsquo;s hard to deny the art of criticism when so many critics have <em>such</em> a way with words.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This new show is the product of a culture that exhumes yesterday because it’s run out of fresh ideas for tomorrow, and its vision of the future is so sterile and uninspired that it often feels like nothing more than a cheap vision of the waking life that everyone in Watanabe’s original was trying so hard to sleep off.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And much like mashups, it&rsquo;s undoubtedly an art form &ndash; an art form that can only exist due to the works of art created by the people around us.</p>
<p>Humans are honestly incredible, when you get right down to it. We make <em>everything</em> &ndash; from the tools we use to get our necessities, to the technologies we use in our day to day life, to just about everything in between. I believe that humanity is, at its core, a creative species. We create the world around us, and the many works of art that serve as a means to express ourselves in that world, essentially as a compulsion. We can&rsquo;t help ourselves &ndash; creating is just what we do.</p>
<p>And if the things you create can only be given form by that which others have created? That&rsquo;s fantastic &ndash; after all, music production and music fusion, art and art criticism, are not adversarial relationships. They&rsquo;re collaborative.</p>
<p>So let&rsquo;s create together.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Feel free to make your own conclusions as to why I&rsquo;m quoting Marx &ndash; only one of them is correct, though.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>What&rsquo;s new is honestly kind of terrible, but that&rsquo;s beside the point.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Seriously, just listen to any of Noah Caldwell-Gervais' <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/broadcaststsatic">thoroughly excellent video game critiques</a>. What he lacks in production values, he more than makes up for with compelling insight. I could listen to that man talk for hours &ndash; in fact, I often do.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>New Players Are Not Stupid Pt.2</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-players-are-not-stupid-2/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 22:45:13 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/new-players-are-not-stupid-2/</guid>
			<description>I think, fundamentally, engaging with any video game (but especially a fighting game) is akin to a conversation between developer and player.
As a developer, your goal should be to confidently communicate your game&amp;rsquo;s mechanics to your player, and trust that the player will be able to keep up. There&amp;rsquo;s a delicate balance here, though &amp;ndash; say too little, and your player won&amp;rsquo;t feel comfortable contributing to the conversation on their own.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think, fundamentally, engaging with any video game (but especially a fighting game) is akin to a conversation between developer and player.<br>
As a developer, your goal should be to confidently communicate your game&rsquo;s mechanics to your player, and trust that the player will be able to keep up. There&rsquo;s a delicate balance here, though &ndash; say too little, and your player won&rsquo;t feel comfortable contributing to the conversation on their own. Say too much, however, and the player won&rsquo;t have any room to express themselves on their own terms.</p>
<p>Once upon a time, I wrote this &ldquo;conversation analogy&rdquo; with respect to a little fighting game called <em>Fantasy Strike</em>, a creation of the not-so-little game developer and noted Low Strong Presser, David Sirlin. You see, it was to be the target of my ire for a follow up to my piece from 2020, <a href="https://sleepmodeblog.wordpress.com/2020/04/27/new-players-are-not-stupid/">&ldquo;New Players Are Not Stupid&rdquo;</a>, where I would talk about what happens when you make a Fighting Game For Dummies. But the world has a funny way of changing your plans. Because while I did end up writing that follow up piece &ndash; this very one you&rsquo;re reading right now &ndash; it&rsquo;s not about <em>Fantasy Strike</em>. At least, not any more.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s about <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>.</p>
<hr>
<p>When you look through the history of the <em>Guilty Gear</em> franchise, comparing which entries are considered genuinely deep and engaging competitive experiences with which entries are liable to cause their players to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nw_YEB0ZOSc&amp;t=242s">loudly proclaim &ldquo;KUSOGE&rdquo; at a publisher-sponsored tournament</a>, you start to get the impression that, throughout the series' 23-year-long tenure, none of its iterations were ever really &ldquo;developed&rdquo; so much as they all just seemed to&hellip; <em>happen</em> within the Arc System Works offices, like mould growing in a petrie dish. Or, perhaps more accurately, in the back of the break room fridge. In this view, it starts to seem more and more miraculous that there are any good <em>Guilty Gear</em> games at all &ndash; the games that manage to land in that first category all seem to be there entirely by accident. To quote my good friend <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Pichy_and_Pals/">Hans &ldquo;Pichy&rdquo; Stockmann</a>, who points to the notorious <em>Guilty Gear XX Slash</em> as an example of this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Slash is the first ASW game with intentionality to its design, and it still proves my thesis that this company cannot do math, hates math, and should never try designing games in a way that requires it.&quot;<br>
&ndash; <strong>Pichy on That Time Ky Was Top One, 2021</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>And so, when Daisuke Ishiwatari and Akira Katano told fans that the newest entry in the series, <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>, would be a &ldquo;complete reconstruction of the franchise&rdquo;, it came with an implication that many of us didn&rsquo;t catch on to &ndash;
by starting from the ground up, <em>Strive</em> had inadvertently billed itself as the first <em>Guilty Gear</em> title to actually be, well&hellip; <em>designed</em>. Early on, I predicted that the presence of actual design intent would be what separated <em>Strive</em> from other games in the series. A few months after release, I now know that I was correct &ndash; and that my prediction was, in hindsight, more like a warning.</p>
<p>As a point of comparison, let&rsquo;s take a step back and talk about the other most popular entry in the <em>Guilty Gear</em> series: <em>Guilty Gear XX Accent Core +R</em> (which I&rsquo;ll be referring to as <em>ACPR</em> for short).<br>
Viewing the totality of that game&rsquo;s various design elements &ndash; system mechanics and characters alike &ndash; it becomes increasingly clear that the game is completely <em>asburd</em>, full of all kinds of unbelievable bullshit that simply wouldn&rsquo;t be allowed to exist in any other fighting game released in the current age. Like, I&rsquo;ve seen people very genuinely consider quitting the game because of Justice, a character whose extremely polarised gameplan makes her mid-tier <a href="http://curryallergy.blogspot.com/2008/11/super-turbo-new-arcadia-diagram.html">in the same way that E.Honda is mid tier in <em>Super Turbo</em></a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, all because in spite of those limitations she still manages to be one of the most toxic zoners I have ever encountered in any fighting game.<br>
Despite <em>ACPR</em>&rsquo;s endless stream of frustrations and ways in which the game seems determined to ignore your desires and intentions at every juncture, it remains extremely popular because of Arc System Works' historically hands-off approach to the fine-tuning of character and systems balance (even to the extent that <em>ACPR</em> was an attempt to do just that with <em>Accent Core</em>) &ndash; rather than being a tightly choreographed competitive experience, the game system and its characters are instead allowed to exist in a somewhat unfiltered manner, and the meta becomes to be defined by <strong>emergent gameplay</strong> rather than strict developer intentions.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>&ldquo;Emergent gameplay&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t refer explicitly to doing things in a game outside of what the developers intended for players to do, of course. The name gives it away, really &ndash; the appeal of a game like <em>ACPR</em> is the fact that, for all its faults, it is a game that feels a lot like a fighting game sandbox, where players are just given tools and are then simply allowed to figure out which ways they want to use those tools. Strategies and advanced gameplay emerge from experimentation, rather than through developer dictates. This is usually what people mean when they say older <em>Guilty Gear</em> titles allow for a high degree of &ldquo;player expression&rdquo; &ndash; the game generally allows you to do whatever you imagine to be possible with the tools at your disposal, irrespective of whether or not doing that might be a good idea.</p>
<p>And thus enters <em>Guilty Gear Strive</em>, a game where you can only use your tools in the limited, narrow ways that <em><strong>Daisuke&rsquo;s Vision</strong></em> allows you to. A game that gives you a hammer, then tells you that the hammer may only be used to hit the nail.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Much has been made of the mechanics of <em>Strive</em>, both in my writings and elsewhere. <a href="https://sleepmodeblog.wordpress.com/2020/04/22/guilty-gear-strive-the-gear-that-never-will-be/">Last time I covered the game</a>, it was just after the end of the first closed beta test held in April 2020, and while some minor details have changed, the game is still largely the same as it was back then. Plenty has been said already about what <em>Strive&rsquo;s</em> mechanics are and what they mean for the game as a whole, so we won&rsquo;t be focusing on that here. Instead, I want to focus on the &ldquo;why&rdquo; &ndash; why are <em>Strive&rsquo;s</em> mechanics designed the way that they are, and what influenced those design decisions?</p>
<p>As a starting point for this analysis, I&rsquo;ll present my thesis statement: where <em>ACPR</em> told players to <strong>experiment</strong>, <em>Strive</em> tells players to <strong>optimise</strong>.</p>
<p>Now, when I say &ldquo;optimise&rdquo;, I don&rsquo;t mean it in the sense that someone in your character&rsquo;s twitter hashtag has found a way to squeeze 10 more damage out of your jump-in punish. Instead, I&rsquo;m talking about a broader trend in modern fighting game design which I believe <em>Strive</em> epitomises &ndash; a trend which emphasises designing systems and toolkits such that the learning curve is as smooth as possible, and players can more quickly begin to make the &ldquo;good&rdquo; decisions in gamplay (commonly phrased as getting new players to &ldquo;play the real game sooner&rdquo;). In other words, it&rsquo;s design that optimises decision-making.<br>
If you&rsquo;re developing a fighting game intended to have mass-market appeal, this seems like a pretty reasonable compromise. You don&rsquo;t want your game to seem so dense and complex that it becomes inscrutable to anyone who isn&rsquo;t already a capital-letter Fighting Game Player, but you also don&rsquo;t want to make things too easy, lest you make match pacing extremely volatile and cause another round of complaining about comeback mechanics. So rather than making winning itself easier, you instead make it easier for people to ascertain what decisions might allow them to win &ndash; which generally means designing the tools available to players in a way that gives them very clear use cases. This is an anti-air, this is a reversal, this is a poke. The big problem with this approach, however, is that in making the use cases of these moves clear, you also make them much more narrow. This is an anti-air, this is a reversal, this is a poke &ndash; and nothing else. The hammer may only be used to hit the nail.</p>
<p>This is all above board (I guess) when you&rsquo;re making something totally new, but what happens when you&rsquo;re working from an established base? In this case, the flattening of the learning curve, the optimisation of decision-making, will invariably result in some things being removed or changed beyond recognition. The professional term for this is &ldquo;streamlining&rdquo;, or so I&rsquo;m told. <em>Strive</em> gives us numerous examples of this design ethos, both on a system and an individual character level.<br>
We can point to a number of ways this manifests on a system level &ndash; the inaccessibility of Instant Blocking and the strange decision to attach guard cancels to the Roman Cancel mechanic<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> come to mind &ndash; but I think if we want to talk about the streamlining of system mechanics, we have to talk about the gatling system, don&rsquo;t we?<br>
Gatlings (aka chain combos) in every <em>Guilty Gear</em> game prior to <em>Strive</em> certainly had intriciacies, thanks to slightly different chain routes for each character, but the system was largely predicated on a pretty simple rule &ndash; if you press a light attack button, you can press the next strength button up from that, and then you do the next attack. It&rsquo;s a very simple &ldquo;ABC&rdquo; formula that&rsquo;s pretty easy to get to grips with. Whatever sequence of buttons you want to use, you can probably pull that sequence off, even if it might not be the &ldquo;optimal&rdquo; sequence to use. <em>Strive</em> cuts down the number of total gatling options available to every character and makes every chain route universal (the details of which I won&rsquo;t get into, just <a href="https://dustloop.com/wiki/index.php?title=GGST/Movement#Gatling_Combination">read the Dustloop wiki</a>) &ndash; what&rsquo;s of note here, however, is <em>which</em> gatling options were made available. The thinking behind which gatling options are available seems to be based on which ones were most commonly used by players in a match setting. 2K &gt; 2D was a really common sequence for a lot of characters, after all. If that&rsquo;s what you were most likely to be doing with the K button in most situations, why should you need to do anything else?<br>
Other restrictions can probably be explained with the ethos of mitigating reward from particular moves. P is a low commitment means of checking offense, so you shouldn&rsquo;t be able to confirm a usable knockdown from it. K is a reasonably fast poke, so you shouldn&rsquo;t be able to get your big combos from it. If you want the big combos, you need to use the S and H buttons. The hammer may only be used to hit the nail.</p>
<p>Of course, that&rsquo;s just the system. If we really want to get into the definition, the <em>true face</em> of <em>Strive</em>&rsquo;s design ethos, we need to talk characters &ndash; specifically, the game&rsquo;s resident King of the Jungle (and the tier list), one Sol Badguy.<br>
In <em>ACPR</em>, Sol was a fairly middle-of-the-road character who was definitely aggressive, but not exactly rushdown. He certainly excelled in the close range thanks to his myriad tools that allowed for powerful frame traps and strike/throw mixups, and while he did also struggle against characters who play well at long ranges, he had a number of unique, aggressive movement options to navigate around them. In <em>Strive</em>, Sol is honestly much the same character, but subjected to that &ldquo;streamlining&rdquo; process I mentioned. This process is endemic to the whole of <em>Strive</em> &ndash; many characters have significantly less tools they can use compared to previous games, less verbs with which players can express their ideas for the game and their character<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> &ndash; and I think we see this pretty sharply when comparing both iterations of Sol.<br>
For starters, there&rsquo;s the separation of Bandit Revolver and Bandit Bringer into separate moves, partly facilitated by the qualitative changes to Bandit Revolver from previous entries &ndash; rather than being an arcing kick that causes a hard knockdown, it now simply moves directly forward, being a standard meterless combo ender and common Roman Cancel point. Bandit Bringer itself is also effectively a replacement for Sol&rsquo;s divekick special from the <em>Xrd</em> games, repurposing an existing special move to serve the function of another, while largely removing the utility of the first iteration, mostly because its utility was somewhat limited and situational. There&rsquo;s also Wild Throw, whose entire utility as a command grab that starts freeform air combos has been gutted in favour of just having all the damage front-loaded into the throw itself. After all, that&rsquo;s the damage you should be getting from the move anyway. Its only utility outside of that now rests with its invulnerability to throws &ndash; a property afforded to all command grabs in <em>Strive</em> so that they can beat attempts by the opponent to break your normal throw. The hammer may only be used to hit the nail.</p>
<p>But the star of the show, really, is the meme move beloved by Sol players everywhere &ndash; this is the part where we talk about Riot Stamp.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup><br>
Riot Stamp is honestly the most <em>Guilty Gear</em> move in <em>Guilty Gear</em>. A flying kick that requires Sol to bounce off the wall behind him before flying towards the opponent, kicking them in the dome and maybe netting a combo. While it does have some situational (and very gimmicky) uses, it is largely a trick. In most situations, the move is trivially easy for the opponent to counter, and the reward you get from landing it compared to the risk you face by allowing your opponent to smack you with their strongest anti-air while you&rsquo;re helplessly flying at them boot-first is not worth it. You don&rsquo;t want to use this move.<br>
Except, you totally do. Because it&rsquo;s <strong>hilarious</strong>.<br>
Specifically the move is hilarious <em>because</em> you don&rsquo;t want to use it. See, humour is predicated on the subversion of expectation, and Riot Stamp can be a fantastic subversion of both players' expectations &ndash; the opponent probably didn&rsquo;t expect to see it come out because of how gimmicky it is, and the Sol player probably didn&rsquo;t expect it to work. The highly situational nature of the move adds to this, as well. After all, it may be the World&rsquo;s Most Obvious Overhead, but it&rsquo;s a bit less obvious when the Sol player does it with their back to the corner, making the startup significantly faster due to the elimination of any travel time to the wall behind him. Even funnier if you do it at the most midscreen position possible, and it still manages to work purely because it caught the opponent so off guard that they screwed up their anti-air. It&rsquo;s a window into the design ethos of a game like <em>ACPR</em> &ndash; it exists for no other reason than &ldquo;just because&rdquo;, and players are allowed to make their own fun with it.</p>
<p>In a way, though, Riot Stamp is also a window into the design ethos of <em>Strive</em> &ndash; because it isn&rsquo;t there.<br>
There really isn&rsquo;t much more to say. Instead of giving players a sub-optimal tool and letting them figure out their preferred uses for it, the tool was simply taken away with no replacement because using it is not explicitly a good idea. If you want to hit the nail, you may only use a hammer.</p>
<p>Ostensibly, the goal of this design ethos is to lower the skill floor without changing the skill ceiling. If playing fighting games competently is broadly about making good decisions about what tools to use and when, then making the use cases clear and obvious should allow for more people to reach a level of competency without affecting the consistency of top level play. And while it doesn&rsquo;t exactly achieve the opposite, it does, I think, serve to lower the skill ceiling regardless. After all, if playing fighting games competently is broadly about making good decisions about what tools to use and when, then one of the most important skills is learning about (or even discovering) those edge case uses for your more niche tools, or even innovating new ways of using tools whose use cases might otherwise seem cut and dry. If the hammer may only be used to hit the nail, then not only are you foregoing any other means of hitting the nail, you&rsquo;re also foregoing any other uses the hammer may provide.</p>
<p><em>Guilty Gear Strive</em> is a game which, in the pursuit of clarity of intent, allows its metagame to be dictated by those intentions rather than by what the players make of it. The issues with the game&rsquo;s design are numerous, but I think it all comes back to this design ethos &ndash; a philosophy of not trusting your players to learn and discover the intricacies of the game themselves. A philosophy of not respecting the intelligence of new players.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup><br>
<em>Guilty Gear Strive</em> is The Fighting Game For Dummies. And if you ask me, players of any skill level, Dummies or otherwise, deserve better than this.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>In case it&rsquo;s not clear, E.Honda&rsquo;s matchup spread in <em>Super Turbo</em> is this polarised because he thoroughly trashes any character who doesn&rsquo;t have a fireball, but gets hopelessly murdered by any character who <em>does</em> have a fireball. Justice is like that, except she&rsquo;s the one with the fireballs.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>As an aside, emergent gameplay thoroughly eclipsing developer intent is nothing new for ASW &ndash; it&rsquo;s actually the entire reason why <em>Hokuto no Ken</em>, a game defined entirely by the ways in which it fails to function as intended, still sees frequent competitive play 15 years after its release.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>&ldquo;Hammer&rdquo; in this analogy may refer to Sol&rsquo;s Far Slash &ndash; it may not. Take it in what sense thou wilt.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
<p><em>Strive</em>&rsquo;s take on Roman Cancels actually presents its own host of problematic design conclusions that are worth discussing, but I may tackle that in a separate article to prevent this one from getting too bloated.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
<p>A friend of mine counted this, actually &ndash; in <em>ACPR</em>, Anji has a total of 46 options in his whole move list (both Anji-specific moves and his versions of universal tools), while in <em>Strive</em>, Anji only has 30 (32 if you&rsquo;re being generous).&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I know you&rsquo;re probably thinking of Dragon Install, but that doesn&rsquo;t count because Dragon Install is on another character in <em>Strive</em>, and also way less funny &ndash; because it&rsquo;s just plain bad.&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7" role="doc-endnote">
<p>And arguably legacy players, to be honest.&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Exodus</title>
			<link>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/exodus/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 16:03:50 +1000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://sleepmodeau.github.io/posts/exodus/</guid>
			<description>Welcome.
This is my new blog, hosted on Github Pages and running on Hugo (after much fighting with inscrutable software dev nerd shit). It&amp;rsquo;s here because I got sick of Wordpress being clunky and locking useful quality of life features behind a paywall. Hopefully this way you won&amp;rsquo;t need uBlock Origin so much.
For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, the old blog is not being deleted, just deprecated &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping all of my old writings there for archival purposes.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome.</p>
<p>This is my new blog, hosted on Github Pages and running on Hugo (after much fighting with inscrutable software dev nerd shit). It&rsquo;s here because I got sick of Wordpress being clunky and locking useful quality of life features behind a paywall. Hopefully this way you won&rsquo;t need uBlock Origin so much.</p>
<p>For what it&rsquo;s worth, the old blog is not being deleted, just deprecated &ndash; I&rsquo;ll be keeping all of my old writings there for archival purposes. If you&rsquo;d like to read them again, they&rsquo;re all still on <a href="https://sleepmodeblog.wordpress.com/">the old blog.</a></p>
<p>Somewhat unfortunately, this does mean that you won&rsquo;t be able to receive notifications for when new articles come up, thanks to the lack of a follow feature or some equivalent. If you&rsquo;d like to stay up to date on when new articles come out, I&rsquo;ll post links on <a href="https://www.twitter.com/SleepmodeAU">my Twitter feed</a>.</p>
<p>Keep your eyes peeled for more writing.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
